Yinyin,
Yinyin,
tonight is your Grandma Mu's birthday banquet.
Malam ini adalah pesta ulang tahun Nenek Mu.
Are you ready?
Apa kau sudah siap?
Mom,
Ibu.
do you think I look good in this dress?
Lihatlah, apakah aku cantik memakai gaun ini?
You look great.
Cantik.
Our Yinyin looks good in anything.
Yinyin kita terlihat cantik dalam memakai apa pun,
But after all, it's your Grandma Mu's birthday banquet.
Tapi bagaimanapun juga ini adalah pesta ulang tahun Nenek Mu.
We can't steal the spotlight from the birthday lady.
Kita tidak boleh merebut perhatian orang yang berulang tahun.
That would be impolite.
Ini tidak sopan.
Steal the spotlight?
Apa? Merebut pusat perhatian?
I should be the main character of this banquet anyway.
Seharusnya aku yang menjadi pemeran utama pesta ini
If Lin Han hadn't suddenly appeared,
Jika bukan karena Lin Han muncul di tengah jalan
my childhood engagement with Huiming wouldn't have been called off.
Huiming dan aku tidak akan dibatalkan
Yinyin, are you crazy?
Yinyin, kau sudah gila?
You absolutely can't do this.
Hal ini tidak boleh dilakukan.
What if someone finds out?
Jika sampai ketahuan,
Your reputation will be completely ruined.
Reputasimu akan hancur.
What reputation?
Reputasi apa?
She's a woman who's been married twice,
Dia seorang istri muda,
yet she still took my place as Mrs. Ying.
Tetap akan merebut posisi istri angkatku.
You always talk about being a proper lady,
Kau selalu mengatakan putri orang kaya
but I don't think it helps at all.
Kurasa tidak ada gunanya.
Yinyin.
Yinyin.
Mom.
Ibu.
Aren't you happy that I want to marry the person I love?
Apakah kau tidak senang aku menikah dengan orang yang kusukai?
Or are you, just like Grandma Mu and Brother Huiming,
Atau kau sama seperti Nenek Mu dan Kak Hui Ming,
all fooled by her?
Dia telah membohongimu.
If that's the case,
Kalau begitu,
why don't you just let her be your daughter instead?
Lebih baik kau biarkan dia menjadi putrimu saja.
Oh, Yinyin.
Astaga, Yinyin.
That's not what I meant.
Bukan itu maksud Ibu.
Alright, I'll help you.
Baik, ibu bantu kau
But who will be wronged then?
Siapa yang harus menderita?
I can't let my precious darling be wronged.
Juga tidak boleh menyakiti sayangku
No matter what happens tonight,
Bagaimanapun juga malam ini
I must be the one engaged to Brother Ying.
Objek pertunangan Ying abang hanya aku
Lin Han, you'd better know your place.
Lin Han kau lebih baik tahu diri
Otherwise, don't blame me for being rude.
Kalau tidak jangan salahkan aku tidak sungkan
Mom.
Ibu.
You look so beautiful today.
Hari ini kau cantik sekali.
When Uncle Ying sees you later,
Nanti saat paman Ying melihatmu,
he'll definitely be dazzled by you.
Pasti akan terpesona olehmu sampai tidak bisa membuka mata.
This is my first time wearing clothes like this.
Ini pertama kalinya aku memakai baju seperti ini.
You're making me feel shy with your compliments.
Kau membuatku jadi malu
Mom, when I grow up,
Ibu, setelah aku dewasa nanti,
I'll buy you even more beautiful clothes.
Aku akan membelikanmu lebih banyak pakaian yang cantik
Even when my mom is eighty,
Ibuku sampai 80 tahun
she'll still be the most beautiful old lady.
Adalah wanita tua yang paling cantik
Am I really that beautiful?
Apa benar secantik itu?
Of course!
Tentu saja.
Mom, do a twirl for me.
Ibu, coba putar.
I want to see.
Aku ingin lihat.
Be careful.
Hati-hati.
Why are you here?
Kenapa kau datang?
Didn't we say Xiaowan and I could go by ourselves?
Bukankah bilang aku dan Xiao Wan pergi sendiri saja?
I couldn't wait.
Sudah tidak sabar.
I just wanted to see you as soon as possible.
Hanya ingin segera bertemu denganmu
Han, dear
Han
You look so beautiful today.
Hari ini sangat cantik
Thank you, Grandma.
Terima kasih, Nenek.
Grandma
Nenek
Look at Han's dress.
Kau lihat gaun XiaoHan ini
I picked it out for her myself.
Aku sendiri yang memilihnya
So, what do you think? Does your grandson have good taste?
Bagaimana? Selera cucumu cukup bagus, 'kan?
You little rascal.
Dasar bocah busuk
I’ll admit, you have good taste.
Kau punya selera
In Grandma’s eyes,
Di mata Nenek,
I can’t see anything anymore.
Tidak ada yang terlihat.
Great-grandma
Nenek buyut.
You can’t even see us anymore?
Bahkan kita pun tidak bisa melihatnya?
I can, I can.
Bisa terlihat.
Great-grandma
Nenek buyut
I spend all day hoping you’ll come visit me.
Setiap hari menantikan kalian datang menjenguk nenek buyut.
Huiming
Kak Hui Ming.
Grandma
Nenek.
Why don’t we go inside first?
Bagaimana jika kita masuk dulu?
Mom, I just did a fortune reading.
Ibu, aku sudah meramal.
In a little while,
Sebentar lagi,
someone’s going to have bad luck.
Ada yang akan sial.
Everyone, just relax.
Kalian santai saja.
As long as I have close contact with Huiming in front of everyone,
Asalkan aku di depan banyak orang,
even if it’s just for the sake of the Han and Liu families’ reputation,
Berhubungan dekat dengan Kak Huiming di depan banyak orang,
Huiming won’t be able to refuse to marry me.
Meskipun demi menghormati keluarga Liu,
Huiming
Kak Hui Ming.
Huiming, it really hurts.
Kak Hui Ming sakit sekali.
Yinyin.
Yinyin.
How about getting up quickly?
Cepat bangun, bagaimana?
Did you hurt yourself when you fell?
Sakit tidak?
Miss Liu, it's great to be young.
Nona Liu memang muda,
You can sleep anywhere you go.
Tidur di mana pun.
I don't even know why lately,
Entah kenapa belakangan ini
every time someone sees me,
Selalu ada orang yang melihatku
I twist my ankle.
Langsung terkilir.
It's not like I do it on purpose.
Aku juga tidak sengaja.
If it were you,
Kalau itu kau,
I'd be happy to.
Dengan senang hati
Lin Han.
Lin Han
Did you push my daughter?
Apakah kau yang mendorong putriku
Aunt Lu.
Bibi Lu,
Lately, your daughter
Belakangan ini putri kau
is either falling or twisting her ankle.
Kalau bukan terjatuh, pasti terkilir.
I think it might be a bone issue.
Kurasa mungkin ada masalah dengan tulangku.
If you have time, I can give you an acupuncture treatment.
Kalau tidak, aku akan menyuntikmu saat ada waktu.
I guarantee it'll cure you right away.
Dijamin akan sembuh.
Let's go, there's nothing more to see.
Ayo, tidak ada yang perlu dilihat.
You think you can become a spirit after just a few years as a fox?
Baru beberapa tahun saja sudah ingin menjadi siluman.
Trying to seduce my grandson right under my nose.
Menggoda cucuku di hadapanku.
Keep dreaming.
Jangan mimpi!
You all should eat more.
Kalian makanlah lebih banyak.
Enjoy your meal.
Makan enak
Come on, let's go over there.
Ayo, kita pergi ke sana.
Are you hurt at all?
Bagaimana? Apakah terluka?
Let's go rest in the lounge.
Kita istirahat sebentar di ruang istirahat.
I'm not going anywhere.
Tidak pergi ke mana pun.
If it doesn't work this time, there will be another chance.
Kali ini tidak bisa, masih ada lain kali.
If I leave,
Jika aku pergi,
Huiming will really belong to someone else.
Kak Hui Ming akan menjadi milik orang lain.
Yinyin, you saw it all.
Yinyin, kau sudah melihatnya?
Huiming doesn't have any feelings for you at all.
Hui Ming sama sekali tidak tertarik padamu.
Do you still want to keep going?
Apa kau masih mau melanjutkannya?
Mom.
Ibu.
I'm just pursuing my own happiness.
Aku sedang mengejar kebahagiaanku sendiri.
Are you going to help me or not?
Sebenarnya kau mau membantuku atau tidak?
Okay.
Baik.
Thank you, everyone.
Terima kasih semuanya
For taking time out of your busy schedules to attend my birthday banquet.
Telah hadir di pesta ulang tahunku
Today,
Hari ini
I have another very important announcement to make.
Aku masih ada satu hal penting yang ingin kuumumkan pada kalian.
Starting today,
Mulai hari ini,
all business matters of the Ying family
Semua urusan bisnis keluarga Ying
will be handled by Huiming.
Akan diserahkan kepada Hui Ming.
At the same time, I would like to formally introduce
Pada saat yang sama, aku juga memperkenalkan kalian
my future granddaughter-in-law,
Cucu menantuku di masa depan
Lin Han.
Lin Han
Aunt Mu, my daughter is missing.
Bibi Mu, putriku menghilang.
Madam.
Nyonya Besar.
Miss Liu and Young Master Ying seem to be trapped in the lounge.
Nona Liu dan Ying Shao sepertinya terjebak di ruang istirahat.
Huiming,
Kak Hui Ming.
today is Grandma's birthday.
Hari ini adalah ulang tahun Nenek.
I specially prepared a good bottle of wine.
Aku khusus menyiapkan sebotol arak bagus.
I just want to share it with you.
Aku hanya ingin berbagi denganmu.
Look at the dress I bought just for today.
Kau lihat rok yang khusus aku beli
Is it pretty?
Cantik tidak?
Cheers.
Bersulang.
Huiming,
Kak Hui Ming.
how are you feeling?
Bagaimana perasaanmu?
It's so hot in this room.
Kamar ini panas sekali.
This air conditioner...
Kenapa AC ini
Why is it so hot even with the AC on?
Kenapa panas sekali?
Huiming,
Kak Hui Ming.
Yinyin,
Yinyin.
I'm feeling a bit dizzy.
Kepalaku agak pusing.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Ke kamar mandi.
Then hurry back.
Cepatlah.
I'll wait for you.
Aku menunggumu.
Huiming,
Kak Hui Ming.
why did you take so long to come back?
Kenapa kau baru pulang?